Guide to the Ernie O'Malley Papers AIA.060
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
The bulk of Series XVI. Subject Files consists of research notes and correspondence between Cormac O'Malley and individuals, organizations and institutions associated with his father. Other items include correspondence, clippings, brochures, photographs, greeting cards, interview transcripts, audio reels, printed matter and other ephemeral material pertaining to topics or people associated with Ernie O'Malley or his son, Cormac O'Malley. Throughout the course of his research on his father, Cormac O'Malley worked with his father's friends and their descendents, numerous universities, libraries, biographers, and documentary film makers. In 1970, Cormac O'Malley conducted a series of interviews with Madge and Jack Comer, Sigle Humphreys, Thomas and Peggy Malone, Sean Lemass, Peadar O'Donnell and George Gilmore documenting personal accounts and the military experiences of Ernie O'Malley. The transcriptions of these interviews, as well as, three 1/4" audio reels are included in this series. Of special interest are materials collected by Ernie O'Malley relating to the Irish Press detailing his travels and expenses, and funds he raised for the newspaper. Many of the items in this series are photocopies of originals housed elsewhere in the collection.
The original inventory listed two separate series for Subject Files: American and Non-American; the latter described as: "Correspondence, clippings, brochures, photographs, greeting cards, interview notes, printed matter and other ephemeral material pertaining to topics or people associated with Ernie O'Malley or his son, Cormac O'Malley with an American connection." These have been combined into one alphabetical run.
Items in Series XV. Printed Ephemera reflect O'Malley's varied interests in Irish history, cartography, art and many other areas and include prints, reprints, maps, photographs, essays, brochures, letters, drawings, reproductions and other ephemeral materials and artifacts collected or inherited by Ernie O'Malley. While most of the graphic items in this series are reprints or reproductions, several original cards, drawings and paintings from notable artists including Roy Boynton, and Jack Hanlon are also included. Nearly twenty maps and nine letters either written by or addressed to historically significant Irishmen and women including Eva Gore Booth, Standish O' Grady, Sean O'Sullivan and Thomas Grattan as well as an undated historic account of the Spanish Armada's landing and an indenture for land dated 1857 complete the series.
Crane, Hart, 1899-1932; De Valera, Eamon, 1882-1975; Hone, Evie, 1894-1955; Irish Republican Army.; Le Brocquy, Louis, 1916-; Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1879-1962; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Roelofs, Helen Hooker O'Malley, 1905-1993; Yeats, Jack Butler, 1871-1957; Yeats, William Butler, 1865-1939; Account books.; Autobiography (genre); Clippings (information artifacts).; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Ireland |x History |y 20th century; Ireland |x History |y Civil War, 1922-1923 |v Personal narratives.; Ireland |x History |y Civil War, 1922-1923.; Ireland |x History |y Easter Rising, 1916; Irish newspapers.; Legal documents.; Manuscripts (document genre); Newspapers.; Poetry.; Political prisoners |z Ireland.; Postcards.; Revolutionaries |z Ireland.; Taos Pueblo (N.M.); Writings (document genre)
- Series I. Works, 1924-1956, undated
  Scope and Content Note
  The series contains two subseries. Subseries A. Ernie O'Malley comprises literary manuscripts, articles, book reviews, essays, short stories, poetry, notes, drawings and speeches written or created by Ernie O'Malley between the years of 1926 and 1956. Published and unpublished works, manuscript drafts, reprints and photocopies are represented. A considerable amount of O'Malley's works were written during his travels throughout the United States and Mexico between 1928 and 1935. A substantial portion of his literary output centers on his homeland, his military experiences during both the Irish War of Independence and Civil War, early Christian art in Ireland and Irish artists. Other works reflect his interest in art, poetry and a variety of other topics. Materials within the Works series are manuscript and/or typescript and are so indicated.
  Works by other authors are found in Subseries B. Other Writers. Material is listed by author and title of the work and organized alphabetically. Throughout his life O'Malley collected ballads and poetry written by others. While most of these materials were either transcribed by O'Malley himself or typed for his personal reference or use, several of the items are clippings or printed materials sent to him by friends and colleagues. Poets within this series include both American and European poets such as Lascelles Abercrombie, Hart Crane, Emily Dickinson, Horace Gregory, James Joyce, Stanley Kunitz, Ezra Pound, Seamus O'Sullivan, John Millington Synge and numerous others. Additional works by others include articles, plays and essays sent to O'Malley for his consideration, review and comment.
  For additional materials relating to the works and literary output of Ernie O'Malley see Series 10: Diaries, Notebooks and Research.
  - Subseries IA. Ernie O'Malley
    - Index to Works, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Adventures of Sean and Seamus"; typed, fragments, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "A Painter of His Choice" book review, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Admirals for a Day" short story, manuscript, 2 drafts, circa 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Against Fate" short story, second version, circa 1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "The Attack on Drangan, June 3, 1920", radio transcript for February 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Autobiography, 1939-1948; typed, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Book Review: "Irish Art in the Early Christian Period," typed, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Book Review: "Shake Hands with the Devil", manuscript, circa 1933 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Book Review: "The Islander by Tomas O'Crohan," typed, circa 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Christian Art in Ancient Ireland" by Adolph Mahr; EOM annotations, manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Connaught; EOM notes on book, manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "Contemporary Mexican Influence in the Arts" essay, manuscript, typescript, published 1947, circa 1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "County Mayo" essay, manuscript draft, circa 1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "The Dark Girl" short story, 2 versions - manuscript and typescript, circa 1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Drawings: pencil drawings near Taos, NM, circa 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "The Ernie O'Malley Introduction, 1945" (regarding Jack B. Yeats; reprinted from Yeats Exhibition Catalog) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Hotel Lobby" manuscript, unpublished draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Ireland, Introduction to" essay; published July 1947 in Architectural Design, photocopy (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Louis le Brocquy, article, manuscript and typescript, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Maire Cain" draft of short story, manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "My favorite gramophone records: Jaran to Tunis", EOM address to Radio Eirann, manuscript, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "Nothing ever happens", draft short story, manuscript, circa 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "On Another Man's Wound", drafts and notes, manuscript and typescript, (fragile onionskin) I, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - "On Another Man's Wound", drafts and notes, manuscript and typescript, (fragile onionskin) II, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - "On Another Man's Wound", loose notes, manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "Painting: The School of London", article, published, Jun 1947 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Poetry and Irish translations, notebook, circa 1928-1935, undate (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Poetry (notebook), 1927 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Poetry (31 poems), circa 1929-1932, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Poetry (notebook), circa 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Poetry: notes, list of poems, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Poems sent to Eileen MacGarville (Dublin) from New Mexico, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Poetry: photocopies I, written 1929-1935 I (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Poetry: photocopies I, written 1929-1935 II (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Poetry: photocopies I, written 1929-1935 III (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Poetry; drafts, manuscript, 1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Poetry, draft, first set, typescript, circa 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Poetry, Final, 51 poems, typescript, 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Poetry: lists by sets, typescript, circa 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Poetry: poems writtin in New Mexico, annotated, typescript, circa 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Poetry: Jan 7-Mar 7, drafts, manuscript (1929-1935?), undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "A", undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "B", undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "C", undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "D", undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "E", 1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "F", 1935, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "G", 1935, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "H", undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "I", undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "J", undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "K", 1930 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "L", undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "M", 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "N", undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "P", undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "R", undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "S", undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "T", undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "U", undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "V", 1931 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "W", 1930-1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "Y", undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set "Z", undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Poetry: Alphabetical set: untitled works (titled by first line), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Raids and Rallies": drafts for Radio Eireann address in 1953), circa 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Raids and Rallies": drafts, corrections, circa 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Raids and Rallies": draft prepared for Radio Eireann address in 1953, circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "Raids and Rallies": as published in The Sunday Press, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "Raid": unfinished short story, mansucript; fragile, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "Renaissance" draft manuscript; typed version in French, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "San Mareno Letters" manuscript, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "Sean Connolly" original typescript for biography; annotations, circa 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Sean Connolly" correspondence regarding, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Sean Connolly" notebook of notes on; for "Raids and Rallies", circa 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Speech for Oct 28: Mission to the United States to raise funds for the Irish Press, manuscript, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Short Story, untitled "Is family enough ...", manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "Sullivan Skin the Mule" short story, manuscript, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Short story, untitled: "Seated at a table away from the bar..."; three versions, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Short story, "Words step into life"; three drafts, manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "The Sack of Mallow" short story, published in Ireland To-Day Sep 1936; inscribed to COM) (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "The Single flame" manuscript; EOM's second autobiography; 1921-1924, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "The Single flame" (Truce, Four Courts) manuscript, partial ending, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "The Single flame" typescript (original title: Ireland); "Dedicated to Ireland the ever-living and her dead sons", circa 1930-1935 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "The Single flame" manuscript, typescript, with annotations, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "The Single flame" typescript, corrections, partial, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "The Single flame" typescript, annotated, corrections, partial, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - "Traditions in Mexican Art" essay, drafts; published in The Listener, 1947, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Untitled: "And you're no good; you have let us down ... " manuscript, [1933] (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Untitled: "As soon as the men who fought in Easter week ... " typescript, circa 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Untitled: "Do we ever get outside of ourselves ... " manuscript, one page, fragile, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Untitled: "Five girls from Monterey in Saltillo ... " manuscript, onionskin, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Untitled: "Harvard archeologists are curious ... " manuscript, typesript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Untitled: "He rubbed his ... " manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Untitled: "I got tired of you speak pretty good English ..." manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Untitled: "I'm going home soon and I'll be glad of it ..." two separate drafts, manuscript, typescript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Untitled: "The Icelandic settlement was a .... " manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Untitled: "In Mexico there has been a continuous tradition ..." manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Untitled: "In the Gaelic State there was no drama ... " manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Untitled: Ireland had always imported manufactured ... " manuscript, typescript, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Untitled: "The Irish dramatic movement is a separate ... ", circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Untitled: "Josquin de Pres was born in ... " typescript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Untitled: "Karl Swartz reached for his tobacco ... " manuscript; typescript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Untitled: "Lieutenant Frank O'Hara tried to strike a match ... " manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Untitled: "Michael Hegarty was a Corkman ... " manuscript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Untitled: "Michael O'Malley was born and bred ... " manuscript, circa 1946 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Untitled: "Most people see the world by arriving ... " manuscript, circa 1946 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Untitled: "Sheila and Sean walk through the trees ... " manuscript, circa 1946 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Untitled: "Somers shifted his feet and smiled ... " typescript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Untitled: "Talking of dreams, Von Holtz said ... " typescript, two copies, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Untitled: "The Unfortunate burro I thought! ... " typescript, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Untitled: "The word Indian ... " manuscript, circa 1946 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Subseries IB. Other Writers
    - Ballads: Irish, manuscript, typescript, 1916-1923 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Ballads: Irish, originals and typescript by EOM, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Ballads: Irish; manuscript, typescript, handbills, 1933-1935, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Ballads: American, sea shanties; typescript, some manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Ballads: Irish (76 items), 1917-1985 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Ballads: Irish, circa 1918-1939 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Ballads: Irish, circa 1928-1956 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Ballads: New Mexico, Frank S. Gutierrez, Ranchos de Taos, circa 1929 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Crane, Hart - poems, 1931, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Greene, Graham: "A Few Pipes", typescript, annotations, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Livesy, Edward "The Walls are down: Portrait of a kleptomaniac"; BBC radio script, Jul 4, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - MacDonagh, Don "The races of Castlebar" typescript, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Poems (to later comprise Ernie O'Malley private anthology), circa 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Poems (71); manuscript, typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Poems (74); manuscript, typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Poems: Irish (215) I, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Poems: Irish (215) II, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Poems: Irish (215) III, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Poems: Final version of anthology (200) I, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Poems: Final version of anthology (200) II, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Poems: Final version of anthology (200) III, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Poems: Final version of anthology (200) IV, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Poems: Final version of anthology (200) V, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Rowan, Martin "The Inauguration of Alphonsus O'Reilly, D.C." typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Poems: cut out of various publications, undated (Box 3, Folder 14A)
    - Reviews and editorials: cut out of various publications, undated (Box 3, Folder 14B)
- Series II. Correspondence: Incoming, 1922-1956
  This series was originally divided into American and Non-American correspondents but these have been combined into one set of incoming correspondence. The separate indices for these listings are included in the index for the series. Files are arranged alphabetically by surname.
  Included are letters, telegrams, greeting cards and postcards sent to Ernie O'Malley between the years of 1922 and 1956. The correspondence in this series is of a personal nature, detailing O'Malley's friendships and associations, as well as, a business nature documenting O'Malley's dealings with publishers, solicitors, and government agencies. Throughout the course of his life O'Malley maintained friendships with notable artists, poets and writers in both Ireland and the United States. Of special interest are the postcards and letters sent to O'Malley while he was imprisoned at Kilmainham Jail and Curragh Camp during the Irish Civil War in 1923 and 1924.
  A limited number of items in this series are photocopies received from various universities, institutions, or private family collections at the request of Cormac O'Malley, Ernie O'Malley's youngest son. Throughout the course of research on his father Cormac O'Malley also transcribed a considerable number of the letters written by Ernie O'Malley. Those transcriptions have been included with the original or photocopy when available.
  - Indices to Correspondence: Incoming (2 and 2A), 2010 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Aiken, Frank, 1928-1935 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Ames, Elizabeth (Yaddo), 1932 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ampleforth College, York England (where Cathal and Cormac will attend), 1946-1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Barton, Daa (Dulcibella), 1945-1947, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), 1947-1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Beckett, Samuel, autograph letter signed, 1947, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Bernard, A., circa 1925, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - [Blainthen ni B] to Ernie O'Malley in jail, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Brady, Frank (Frances), 1924 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Brady, Kathleen (Kay; sister of Frances), 1924-1944 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Brady (Kay or Frank?) to Ernie O'Malley in jail, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Breen, Dan, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Brennan, Robert (Bob) [empty], 1924 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Brett, Dorothy (letter re: death of D.H. Lawrence; Taos, NM), 1930, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Brown, Paddy [Podraig de Brun), President, University College Galway, 1944-1947 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Brown, Sheila, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Burke-Sheridan, Margaret (opera singer, Co. Mayo), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Burrishoole Lodge, Newport, Co. Mayo (residence), 1943-1948 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Childers, Mary Alden Osgood (Molly; Mrs. Erskine Childers), 1924, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Citkowitz, Israel (composer), 1952 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Citkowitz-Liber, Rebecca (Mrs. Armour Liber), 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Clurman, Harold, circa 1952 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Coffey, Brian, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Cole, Lois Dwight (MacMillan Company), 1933 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Counahan, Maire ni (to EOM in jail), 1924 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Craig, Maurice, Feb 28, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Crane, Hart, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Crowe E[ileen], 1932, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Crowley, Dan, Jul 28, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Curran, Cornelius P. (C.P.), 1951-1956 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Davidson, Bob, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Davis, Chester C. (Simpson, Thatcher & Bartlett- Helen's lawyer), 1953-1953 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Delemer, C., circa 1925 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Department of Defence, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - DeValera, Eamon, autograph letter signed, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Dolan, Sister Mary Scholastica, Sligo, 1932, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Doyle, Andy (IRA), Tipperary, 1945, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Egan-Gill, Molly, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - [F.S.] unknown, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Fitzgerald, Mabel (wife of Minister of Foreign Affairs), 1923 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Ford, John, 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Frost, Sheila (artist), circa 1945 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Gallagher, Frank (author), 1929, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Gilmore, George, Nov 30, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Goddard, Theodora, circa 1932-1934 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Golden, Helen Merriam, circa 1930-1940 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Golden-Sax, Eithne, 1932-1955 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - [Gongane, Coanin] unknown, Aug 12, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Greene, Graham (letters of introduction for Ernie O'Malley to Eyre & Spottiswoode Publishers, Ltd, London), May 1947 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Halligan-Clarke, Sunny (Mrs. Michael Clarke), 1938-1945 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Hanlon, Jack (artist, priest), 1946 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Harcourt, Burke (Harcourt, Brace Co.), 1929-1933 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Heller, Clemens (Salzburg Seminar in American Studies), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Henry, Francois (University College Dublin), 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Herbert, Robert (Bob) Limerick Public Library, 1945-1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Hone, Eve (artist), 1943-19950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Howe, Mariana, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hughes, John T., 1932-1939 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Humphreys, Sigle (Sheila, Mrs. Donal O'Donoghue), Apr 5, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Irish Academy of Letters, 1937-1950, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Jack B. Yeats National Loan Exhibition Committee, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Jeffers, Una, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Johnson, Spud (includes copy of ballad "Buck Dunton and the Desparado"), 1930 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Jellety, Bay (sister of Maine; artist), Sep 7, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Jooss, Kurth (German modern dancer), Oct 21, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Kellher, John V. (Harvard University), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Kelly, Grace V., 1929 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Kennedy, Frank, Dec 3, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Kerrigan, Georgette, Dr. Sarsfield Kerrigan, 1946-1957 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Kerrigan, Mimi (daughter of Georgette), Dec 1946 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Kronenberger, Louis (Alfred A. Knopf), 1934 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Laverty, Maura (author/playwright), 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - le Brocquy, Louis (artist; mother Sybil le Brocquy), 1946-1951 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Leach, Henry G. (The Forum), 1935 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Leighton, Geroge R. (Harper's), 1932 (Box 4, Folder 23)